<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-09T11:04:03+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Transcendence</title><subtitle>The fine line between innovation and insanity</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The March goes on</title><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/the-march-goes-on/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The March goes on" /><published>2020-04-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-24T13:37:11+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/the-march-goes-on</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/the-march-goes-on/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By March, the worst of the winter would be over. The snow would thaw, the rivers begin to run and the world would wake into itself again.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Not that year.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Winter hung in there, like an invalid refusing to die. Day after grey day the ice stayed hard; the world remained unfriendly and cold.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From the children’s book Odd and the Frost Giant by Neil Geiman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-few-thoughts&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A few thoughts…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March is that special time of the year where nature pulls off its own magic trick. The once barren, white desert of wintertime is replaced with a sea of pastel colours. Flowers bloom on the branches of trees that were seemingly teetering on the edge of life just weeks ago. As the thick layer of snow melts away, revealing the lush green meadows below, many animals awaken from their slumber, taking in the soft glow of the rising sun for the first time in months while birds make the long journey home, returning from their tropical vacation in faraway lands. Up in the heavens, strokes of white scatter the deep blue canvas, and between its cracks, the bright sun seeps through, blanketing the world with its light and warmth, reminding all across the vast lands that the dark wintry days are finally over. One who is surrounded by such greatness and wonder, upon taking a deep breath, will smell the very essence of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/WLANL_-_artanonymous_-_De_roze_boomgaard-1024x816.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Pink Orchard&quot; title=&quot;The Pink Orchard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Pink Orchard&lt;/i&gt; by Vincent Van Gogh (1888)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, the reality of life reflects a completely different image of nature’s scenery. With the worsening of the Covid-19 situation causing the cancellation of not only RoboCup, but many other robotics competitions as well, our disappointment is shared worldwide. For most of us, this would have been our last year participating in RoboCup. It is even more poignant to note how in the past few years, when we were given countless opportunities, we were always unprepared and left in a state of frenzy. Yet now, when we were finally &lt;a href=&quot;/a-december-to-remember/#conclusion&quot;&gt;“more prepared than ever to forge new frontiers in the new year”&lt;/a&gt;, to make our final stand and end this decade long journey of robotics on a high, it was the world that fell into hysteria instead. Alas, when faced with the irony of the absurd world, what can we do, as passengers on this roller coaster of chaos, but to force a helpless smile and move on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress now is way behind our original schedule since many of our shipments were delayed. We are also working much slower now since our actual deadline for completion has been “shifted” to next year, allowing us to balance our time with other things such as academics and new non-RoboCup related projects (hint hint). Nonetheless, we still made some progress in March and here are our key achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pcb-open&quot;&gt;PCB (Open)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our remaining electronic parts arrived over the course of the month. All the circuits in our PCB surprisingly worked. However, we did encounter a few design flaws in them, mainly the 1st layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 60V circuitry for the solenoid and 12V connectors for the motors are very close to the 3.3V power for the LED light ring. We will need to insulate the bottom of the PCB to ensure accidental shorting does not occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200401_212418-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PCB Bottom&quot; title=&quot;PCB Bottom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The motor and battery connectors (left) near to the LEDs (right)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, due to some miscalculations, the back of a motor was too close to the 3.3V pin for the mouse sensor, which blocked us from being able to insert the connector for the sensor. In the end, we wired the mouse sensor up from a spare 3.3V pin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these problems will certainly be fixed in the follow-up version of the PCB for our robot next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pcb-lightweight&quot;&gt;PCB (Lightweight)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Lightweight PCBs, most of the important parts such as the motors and IR sensors are working perfectly. However, we are currently facing a problem with the I2C communication for the TOF sensors on the fourth layer, although not much troubleshooting has been done for it yet, so we are not quite sure what is causing it as of now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also one very, &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; dumb mistake for these PCBs. Due to certain wrong configurations in EAGLE, all of the vias are &lt;strong&gt;not tented&lt;/strong&gt;. This is especially bad when it comes to the really complicated boards like the first layer since any stray metal part can easily short it. Sigh…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200401_213146-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PCB Lightweight&quot; title=&quot;PCB Lightweight&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Pimples everywhere...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, Lightweight progress may be put on hold or terminated. This is because we have always used Lightweight as an introduction league to guide our first timers with the basics before they go into the Open category and thus, there will be a completely new batch of students who will have to build a completely new set of robots next year. But nothing is confirmed yet, so we’ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stm32-programming&quot;&gt;STM32 programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our STM32 was modeled from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/retired/11280&quot;&gt;Maple Mini&lt;/a&gt; board. However, one problem with the Maple Mini was that the USB communication with Arduino is quite unreliable, e.g. program could not be uploaded, hanging, etc. Thus, during our “Test PCB” phase, when we uploaded the Maple Mini bootloader and downloaded programs into the STM32 over USB, there was the same unreliability, where it stopped and started working at random times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, we decided to use the SWD protocol to upload programs directly into the STM32. On our PCB, we breakout the SWD, power and TX/RX pins into a 6 pin JST-SH1.0 connector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200402_212848-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JST-SH1.0&quot; title=&quot;JST-SH1.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;JST-SH1.0 connector on the 4th layer of Open robot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a J-Link OB V8 debugger we are able to upload the compiled .hex files of our programs using the Segger J-Flash software. Also, with a USB to UART converter connected to the TX/RX pins, we can still use Arduino’s Serial Monitor to view data the same way as a USB connection would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200402_212808-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;J-Link&quot; title=&quot;J-Link&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;J-Link and USB to UART converter wired to the JST-SH1.0 connector&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/f.png&quot; alt=&quot;J-Flash&quot; title=&quot;J-Flash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Screenshot of J-Flash software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intra-robot-communication&quot;&gt;Intra-robot communication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our sensors on the different layers are communicating with 4 different STM32 micro-controllers, we need a way to communicate with them from the main controller, the Teensy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose UART instead of other communication protocols like I2C and SPI. This is because I2C is too sensitive, especially the cross-layer wires that will be highly susceptible to EMI from the motor, while SPI slave mode is quite difficult to implement on our STM32 micro-controllers and would require more wires. However, UART, albeit rather slow, is the simplest to implement of all the protocols, requires only 2 wires and is relatively robust against noise. Besides, our Teensy has 6 serial ports so we do not need to fear about running out of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use a standardised format for each string of data. It starts out with a character that indicates what type of data it is (e.g. Light sensor = &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;L&lt;/code&gt;), followed by the data itself and finally the vertical bar &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; as a delimiter. This data would be read into a buffer and upon reading the vertical bar, a function would be called to process it. An example buffer would be &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;B100,90|&lt;/code&gt; which means the ball (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;B&lt;/code&gt;) is 100 cm away at a 90 degree angle relative to the robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the light sensors, the thresholds are processed on the STM32 and data is represented in 5 bytes (for Open, with 40 sensors) or 6 bytes (for Lightweight, with 48 sensors). Each bit in the bytes represents the state of the light sensors (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; = detected line, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; = not detected). For example, if the 1st byte is 20 (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;B00010100&lt;/code&gt;), that would mean the 3rd and 5th sensor is detecting the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The communication between the Raspberry Pi and Teensy is very critical since there is a huge amount of data being sent between them (ball position, ball’s predicted position, yellow and blue goal positions and field area coordinates). Thus, the speed of communication is very important and we tested out what the maximum baud rate could be used between the two controllers. Using a serial loopback test on the Raspberry Pi, we found the communication to be stable up to 2 million bits/sec, which is just nice since the fastest speed the Teensy can communicate with a 0% error rate is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pjrc.com/teensy/td_uart.html&quot;&gt;2 million bits/sec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gui&quot;&gt;GUI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some improvements were added to the GUI over the month. An additional camera window was created, which can be toggled to a different mode from the main camera window. Hence, when calibrating the threshold in the main window, the results can be viewed immediately in the secondary window instead of having to switch modes like in the older version. Under the secondary window includes a mini notepad as well for recording threshold values or other information. Also, all configuration parameters other than the threshold values have been hidden to make the GUI less cluttered. They can be toggled to be shown under the ‘Advanced’ tab at the top left corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Screenshot-from-2020-04-01-16-20-23-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GUI Window&quot; title=&quot;GUI Window&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Screenshot of new GUI window&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;camera&quot;&gt;Camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new version of the object tracking program (for ball, goal and field) was created to deal with a rising number of issues we faced with the original version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the original program, the CPU utilisation was around 80% and the frame capture rate was at 65 FPS, far below what we had planned to achieve. In hopes of optimising the code, we tried testing specific parts of the code, only to add to our confusion as even more &lt;em&gt;weird&lt;/em&gt; problems popped up. For example, when a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;usleep&lt;/code&gt; was added to the main thread so that it does not run on an empty while loop, the frame capturing rate decreased. This is the exact opposite of what we expected to see, since less CPU was being used, the FPS should have increased! While we are still not fully sure why this happens, our best guess would be that usleep interferes with the other threads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, with many problems identified in the original program, we embarked on creating a second version to specifically address them. The new version has a CPU utilisation of half the original, at only 40%. The frame capture rate is also back at 90 FPS again, exactly what we wanted. Some of the key improvements in this second version include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Instead of running a thread on an empty loop — constantly refreshing until a new frame is obtained — a condition variable is used to send a signal to the respective processing threads, releasing it from a block.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The use of mutex for thread synchronisation and the prevention of data race has been replaced by atomic variables and circular buffers. Previously, mutex locking and unlocking of the capture frame took up around 2.5 ms. While that might sound like a small amount of time, when considering that the latency in the capturing of frames is around 16 ms, cutting down on this 2.5 ms help reduced the latency significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The threads now run on a priority system, allowing for better allocation of CPU resources (priority 1 runs at 90 FPS, priority 2 at 20 FPS and priority 3 at 10 FPS). The priority given to each thread is dynamic, which means that our Teensy can switch the priorities, or even assign 2 threads to the highest priority, as needed during the match (e.g. when chasing for the ball, priority 1 can be assigned for ball detection, but once we have possession of the ball in our dribbler, priority 1 can be assigned for goal detection instead). In the video below, the ball is assigned with priority 1 while the goals are in priority 2. Hence the goals detection are seen flickering as they are only being detected about once every 5 frames.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MxzFrM1Lxgk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these implementations, our processing of top priority objects can be done at 90 FPS with a latency of around 13 ms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, this is definitely a disheartening end to the 2020 RoboCup journey for all of us, but on the other hand, perhaps this is a reminder for us to look beyond just the competition itself. We have always been overly focused on &lt;strong&gt;HOW&lt;/strong&gt; we do what we do that we often forget about &lt;strong&gt;WHY&lt;/strong&gt;. It is times like this, when we still continue doing what we do, with no conceivable end in sight, that really forces us to ponder about the purpose of it all…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, we know that we are very fortunate to still be able to continue, “business (somewhat) as usual”, and as long as this remains possible, we will definitely not stop. In the meantime, stay safe, stay healthy, stay strong! 💪&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kai Cong</name><email>161815w@student.hci.edu.sg</email></author><category term="Soccer Lightweight" /><category term="Soccer Open" /><category term="Electronics" /><category term="Mechanical" /><category term="Monthly" /><category term="Programming" /><summary type="html">By March, the worst of the winter would be over. The snow would thaw, the rivers begin to run and the world would wake into itself again. Not that year. Winter hung in there, like an invalid refusing to die. Day after grey day the ice stayed hard; the world remained unfriendly and cold. From the children’s book Odd and the Frost Giant by Neil Geiman</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rescue Line - March Update</title><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/rescue-line-march-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rescue Line - March Update" /><published>2020-03-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-24T13:37:11+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/rescue-line-march-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/rescue-line-march-update/">&lt;p&gt;A long time has passed since the last Rescue Line update as I’ve been mostly working on getting the Soccer robot up and running, but since everyone is waiting on parts to arrive from China it’s time for another update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to make this blog as comprehensive as possible, but if there is anything you would like to know more about or anything that is confusing, do feel free to reach out to us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;base-upgrades&quot;&gt;Base upgrades&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, our drive base was a monolithic 3d printed part which was heavy, wasted a lot of filament and took a long time to print. This made our base very inflexible and chunky, which was not desirable since at that point, we haven’t designed our claw and ball collection mechanism, thus it made it difficult to integrate into the old base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B5m7bQgHkDa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B5m7bQgHkDa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B5m7bQgHkDa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Day 2+??: Finished the base of the robot for now, 9 hr print ahead, hopefully the gears don&amp;#39;t end up grinding too much. Also finished some slave work and claims!! 🎉 ~pajiao [rescue]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bozotics/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; ¡ßöZø 🗽 SqûãD!&lt;/a&gt; (@bozotics) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-12-03T11:16:07+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 3, 2019 at 3:16am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, we have redesigned our robot in order to make it lighter, more modular and flexible and to fit our ball collection mechanism. Originally, we wanted to make use of a static stress simulation software in order to decide which parts of the base to cut out, but we wasted a lot of time figuring it out and decided to abandon that route.
In the end, we just thought about which parts of the robot required more reinforcement and made those specific parts thicker or braced that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue_3.0_2020-Mar-14_07-22-22AM-000_CustomizedView37765168667_png-1024x791.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rescue Robot&quot; title=&quot;Rescue robot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Redesigned robot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than a single big 3d printed base, we have split it up into 4 plates to be connected by copper stands. We would also have a “base plate” across these 4 plates where our electronics and other mechanisms would be mounted upon. All these are quite difficult to show and explain, but more photos will be shared when we finish assembling the robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue-3.0-v73-1024x419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Robot Plate&quot; title=&quot;Robot plate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;One of the 4 plates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evacuation-zone-ball-collection&quot;&gt;Evacuation zone ball collection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the evacuation zone victims, we considered many different types of ball collection mechanisms, including a rolling intake, a conveyor belt, or the traditional “scoop”. However, we wanted our robot to be as small and lightweight as possible, thus we decided to go with a traditional claw and pick up the balls one by one. Electrical contacts would also be taped to the claw to detect whether the victims are dead or alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue-3.0-v74-1024x419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grab and Lift&quot; title=&quot;Grab and lift&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Grab and Lift mechanism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are preparing for both 2019 and 2020 rescue line rules as we were unsure of which version our local organiser would be adhering to. Thus, we had to sort the victims before depositing. We came up with a “funnel” that would guide the victim into its own compartment depending on whether it was dead or alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R7Kq_BM1njY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To dispense the victims, we wanted to use 1 servo motor but be able to separately dispense the dead and live victims. Thus we have decided to use a “wiper” to open each compartment separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IwuGNuWBgWU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we need to prepare for both the 2019 and 2020 rules, we also need to ensure our compartment is large enough to fit around 6+ balls for the 2019 rules, and be able to dispense the rescue kit for the 2020 rules. In order to hold that many balls our ramp inside the compartment cannot be too steep, however to dispense the rescue kit the ramp needs to be steep enough since it’s a cube with a lot of friction. Thus, we have decided to make an “angler” which varies the angle of the ramp as well as the compartment size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MDEHv5JpAko&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;electronics-and-programming&quot;&gt;Electronics and programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to sense and track the line, we have made our own light sensor array PCBs. These contain 12 LEDs, ALS-PT19 phototransistors, and 2 TCS3200 color sensors, together with a STM32F103 processor which reads and processes these sensors, then sends the data over UART or I2C to a main controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/RescueLS-1-1024x419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Light Sensor PCB&quot; title=&quot;Light sensor PCB&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Top of the Light Sensor PCB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We haven’t started programming the robot yet, but we are planning to use 2 of these PCBs to speed up our line tracking. Details of the exact logic will be finalised when we finish building and start programming our robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue-3.0-5-1024x419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Underside of robot&quot; title=&quot;Underside of robot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Bottom of the light sensor PCB, as seen from under the robot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to detect the victims in the evacuation zone as well as the rescue kit, we are planning to use a Raspberry Pi Camera with some color tracking / edge detection algorithms to speed up our runs and prevent our robot from “brute forcing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue-3.0-6-1024x419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pi camera&quot; title=&quot;Pi camera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I spy with my little eye...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, vision detection and computer vision takes a long time to tune and program. Thus, we have backup plans in our small VL53L0X distance sensors which also help to detect obstacles. We place them one above another to help us differentiate victims from the evacuation zone walls, as well as the rescue kit from other obstacles and walls on the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue-3.0-77-1024x419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TOF&quot; title=&quot;TOF&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;There is one more TOF sensor under the Light Sensor PCBs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rescue robot is slowly coming to shape. This is a new category for us, thus progress is a little slower as we are testing a lot of new designs and ideas, resulting in many robot iterations. However we remain confident that we can build a working and competitive robot by the time the competition comes (if it isn’t cancelled…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do follow us on our Instagram for timely updates on our build process!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jing Heng</name><email>151436j@student.hci.edu.sg</email></author><category term="Rescue Line" /><category term="Electronics" /><category term="Mechanical" /><summary type="html">A long time has passed since the last Rescue Line update as I’ve been mostly working on getting the Soccer robot up and running, but since everyone is waiting on parts to arrive from China it’s time for another update!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">February Worries</title><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/february-worries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="February Worries" /><published>2020-03-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-24T13:37:11+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/february-worries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/february-worries/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;February is the uncertain month, neither black nor white but all shades between by turns. Nothing is sure.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gladys Hasty Carroll&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-not-so-few-thoughts&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A (not so) few thoughts…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February has a very special day: the 29th, i.e. the &lt;em&gt;leap day&lt;/em&gt;. It occurs once every 4 years to compensate for the drifting inaccuracies of our calendar. For many people, leap days would evoke nothing short of apathy and disinterest; most people probably wouldn’t even realise it until it is much closer. However, I feel leap days serve as a subtle reminder for two interesting things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, is just how small and insignificant we all seem. The days, months and years that we all so closely abide by every moment of our lives are, at the end of the day, just another one of humanity’s feeble constructs to help us find a sense of control amidst the chaos of the universe. This reminds me of Existentialism, a philosophical school of thought from which my greatest positive takeaway for life is that the universe is inherently irrational, chaotic and meaningless, and thus it is solely up to the individual to instill meaning into his own life by taking personal responsibility of his own actions and decisions, i.e. embracing one’s existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two, is &lt;em&gt;our lack of awareness&lt;/em&gt;. This refers to anything from the vast amount of knowledge we will never learn, to the many experiences we will never get to experience in our lifetime and even to the sheer number of people we see everyday, but will never get to know. At face value, leap days are simply a quirky addition to our calendars, but digging deeper, these extra days are required because our calendar is merely a simplification of a whole complex field of astronomy and celestial mechanics that most of us will never understand. I find it humbling and even somewhat overwhelming when considering that everything, be it the littlest of things we know, the smallest of events we encounter, or the most insignificant of people we meet; all of them have an incredibly complex backstory, a series of interconnected events, that brought them to us. Every moment of our lives, countless of immeasurably unique things happen to us, yet we can never truly appreciate them because we are not even aware those moments exist. And even if we were aware of them, what could we possibly do about it? When taking into account the sheer size of the universe, it is simply impossible to fully appreciate the significance of our whole lives. In a twisted way, we try so hard to instill meaning into our lives, but ultimately, we end up knowing so little about the world and our life itself that it begs the question of whether we have truly &lt;em&gt;lived&lt;/em&gt; in this world…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/milky-way-1023340-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Milky Way&quot; title=&quot;Milky Way&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I like to do a self-reflection every 29th of February as it only occurs every 4 years. When asked to picture themselves in a decade’s time, most people would give an honest “I don’t know” for it seems so far away. Yet, when asked to picture themselves in a year’s time, most people would only think of themselves in the same, unchanging routine of their lives. However, 4 years is just the perfect timing where it is close enough that most can still roughly picture what kind of path they would be on and what kind of life they would be leading, yet far enough that much of the details would still be murky enough to keep new possibilities open. When reflecting, I will take stock of my long term growth as a person over the past 4 years, while setting an overarching “macro” theme for my life (on top of the more detailed yearly, monthly and daily goals), for the long but conceivable span of the next 4 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February has been a rather chaotic month, to say the least, especially with the corona virus outbreak in China, affecting our main source of electronic parts. Nonetheless, we still made as much progress as we could, and here are some of our important breakthroughs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mirror-lightweight&quot;&gt;Mirror (Lightweight)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following up from the problems with our first mirror molding process, we made some improvements such as using a bigger heat gun for more even heating and pre-heating the mirror mold to a higher temperature. However, the final mirror still came out rather warped, creating a highly distorted image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence we decided to experiment with another method: folding a mirror sheet into a cone. First, we drew a 2D net of our conical mirror and printed it out. Next, we pasted this net outline over a 0.5mm PVC mirror sheet (much thinner than the ones used for molding) and cut the shape out. Finally, using epoxy, we stuck this mirror cone net around a 3D printed cone, thus creating our mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200301_214055-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2D Cone Net&quot; title=&quot;Cone net&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;2D cone net printed on paper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200301_214001-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished mirror&quot; title=&quot;Finished mirror&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Finished mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method produced a much higher quality mirror, while being way simpler and faster to do. Although there is a large distortion along the line where the two ends of the cone net meet, this mirror is used for lightweight so only the goal detection is crucial. Since the goals are rather huge on the mirror’s image, and the line of distortion can be rotated to face the side of the robot, the line does not cause much problems to the otherwise perfect mirror!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pcbs&quot;&gt;PCBs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to COVID-19, much of our schedule have seen some kind of delay. We sent in our PCBs for manufacturing only on the 10th of February (1 week behind our schedule), due to the fact that the factory could only start work by then. Following that, the delivery of our PCBs were also delayed, arriving only on the 24th. To make matters worse, a huge number of our electronic parts, including one of the most important parts, the TPS5430 buck converter chip, were not shipping and we had only received news of it shipping over on the 29th (meaning it would probably come only by the 2nd week of March). 😞 Nonetheless, we still tried to solder as much of our PCBs as possible by making do with what we had and even salvaging old parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lightweight&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lightweight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have 4 PCBs, with the third and fourth layers mostly soldered. The third layer is a very compact board that holds the OpenMV camera, Teensy, STM32 chip, IR ring and all the other connectors from the other layers. The fourth layer acts as a mirror holder, and also holds the VL531L1X TOF sensors and BNO055 compass. Since the TOF breakout board we are using does not have screw holes, we mounted them using 90 degree male headers that allowed them to be easily detachable yet still perfectly aligned parallel to the ground in a fixed, stable position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200302_184602-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assembled Layer 3&quot; title=&quot;Layer 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Layer 3 with OpenMV and IR sensors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200302_184320-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assembled Layer 4&quot; title=&quot;Layer 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Layer 4 with TOF and compass sensors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the first and second layer, we have opted not to begin soldering it first to be safe, since we want to make sure our TPS5430 buck converter outputs the correct voltage first before soldering the remaining components. They shall stay dormant &lt;em&gt;for now&lt;/em&gt;, but not &lt;em&gt;for long&lt;/em&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;open&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Soccer Open, other than a few connectors, most of the third and fourth layer has been soldered and the parts that we could test, such as the STM32 chip and NeoPixel LEDs, were all working properly. As for our first layer, we have also decided to wait till the buck converter arrives before continuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200302_183521-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Re-assembled robot&quot; title=&quot;Re-assembled robot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Re-assembled robot with PCB and CF plates in all its glory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_20200301_171407-1-869x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Neopixel pink&quot; title=&quot;Neopixel pink&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Ring of fire&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also swapped out our motor switch from a toggle switch to a missile switch instead. As much as one can say it is literally just a toggle switch with a spring loaded cover, it still doesn’t stop me from feeling like I’m launching a rocket every time I flip the switch. 🙃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_eF3GVjwg4Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;video-caption&quot;&gt;Click clack boom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gui&quot;&gt;GUI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GUI is just a few more minor fixes away from being 100% complete! The remaining problems we have left to fix is our “make” button, which occasionally crashes the GUI, and the ROI selection, which currently does not display a bounding box when dragging the mouse across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8_oUHZHI3Y/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8_oUHZHI3Y/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8_oUHZHI3Y/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GUI streaming ball detection from Raspi ⠀ Features: 1. Edit and compile code with UI (vscode/in-built code editor in UI) 2. Quick thresholding with instant value update 3. ROI to identify colour range 4. Visual debugging for every step of the image processing 5. One click to start UI and stream ⠀ ~JT [Soccer Open] #robocup #robocupjunior #bozotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bozotics/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; ¡ßöZø 🗽 SqûãD!&lt;/a&gt; (@bozotics) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-02-25T15:04:32+00:00&quot;&gt;Feb 25, 2020 at 7:04am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;camera&quot;&gt;Camera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After programming the GUI for a week or two, with a separate Raspberry Pi, we made another &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; discovery when we started working on the actual robot again. Previously, we thought that we could track up to 120 FPS but that was using a camera mode that only used a partial FOV, which was not suitable for us. 😂😂😂 Using the correct camera mode with the full FOV, our frame rate is now capped at 40 FPS. Adding an approximate 6 ms processing time to the 25ms reading time, our image processing is effectively running at roughly 30 FPS, much lower than our initial expectation of 50 FPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of this, we considered using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;raspiraw&lt;/code&gt; which obtains raw Bayer images from the Pi camera. After a week of researching and attempting to use it, we concluded that it will be too time consuming to make it work. Fortunately, we are able to unlock more processing speed and reading speed by overclocking the RAM, GPU and CPU of our Raspberry Pi, especially since we are now using a much larger heat sink than before. However, after experimenting, we realised that overclocking would heat up our Raspberry Pi rather quickly, reaching over 60 degrees after running for 10 minutes. Hence, whether we will actually overclock our Pi still remains to be seen… 🤔&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also experimented with various algorithms to improve our object tracking such as using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;meanshift&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;camshift&lt;/code&gt; but it was ineffective due to the presence of many objects that had a similar colour range as the ball. Thus, we fell back on our good old vanilla thresholding. It is good enough for our use given that it could track the ball up to 3m away. However, this is still largely dependent on the lighting condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of thresholding, we have also implemented a basic Kalman filter to predict the movement of the ball if it is obscured by another object such as an opponent’s robot or the copper stands supporting the mirror. However, as the mirror is curved, an extended Kalman filter will have to be used to linearize the distorted image for tracking to be more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zP8gnEITTic&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;video-caption&quot;&gt;Red rectangle depicts the predicted ball position&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simulation&quot;&gt;Simulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For around the first week or so of February, we made some improvements to the simulation, adding key features such as simple line avoidance, goal aiming, ball kicking, attack-defense switching, and a basic back dribbler flick. A few clips of our simulation in action can be found on our Instagram Highlights &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/stories/highlights/17910837451404256/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, our simulation project will be put on hold for now as all our more advanced strategy will require knowledge of the opponent robot’s position, which we still don’t know if our camera is capable of doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I’m going to be honest, February has been a rather bad month as compared to our previous months. Progress has been frustratingly slow due to bottlenecks on the supply side, an external problem that we have completely no control over. As of now, we are 2 weeks behind schedule, &lt;em&gt;at best&lt;/em&gt;. But on the other hand, at this rate, the Singapore Open would probably be postponed too, soooo… 🤷‍♂️🙃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of January I had proclaimed February was going to be our make-it-or-break-it month; yet, its the end of February and I am inconclusive about which side of that statement we are lying on. Neither anything exceptionally good nor terribly bad has happened because nothing much has happened in the first place. Perhaps that in itself is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; bad thing, but then again I don’t even know what to think anymore. I seek a deeper meaning to all this that we do, yet I fear deep down in my heart I already know what the answer to that is. But till that day of epiphany &lt;em&gt;(or admittal)&lt;/em&gt; arrives, I shall just mindlessly wait for those elusive Taobao shipments to arrive…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kai Cong</name><email>161815w@student.hci.edu.sg</email></author><category term="Soccer Lightweight" /><category term="Soccer Open" /><category term="Electronics" /><category term="Mechanical" /><category term="Monthly" /><category term="Programming" /><category term="Simulation" /><summary type="html">February is the uncertain month, neither black nor white but all shades between by turns. Nothing is sure. Gladys Hasty Carroll</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A January Commentary</title><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-january-commentary/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A January Commentary" /><published>2020-02-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-24T13:37:11+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-january-commentary</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-january-commentary/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;January is here, with eyes that keenly glow,
A frost-mailed warrior
striding a shadowy steed of snow.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edgar Fawcett&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opening-thoughts&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opening thoughts…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January is ironic. As the first month of the year, it is supposed to represent a new beginning, another reset button to try it all over again and thus, a hope for a better future. Yet, when one takes a step outside, it reflects a completely different message. Being right in the middle of the winter season, a thick blanket of snow covers every part of nature, creating a blindingly white landscape. The air is frigid, biting any exposed skin even in the slightest breeze. Trees sway slowly in the cold wind with their thin, naked branches, as if they are crying for help. Silence permeates the still, lifeless environment as most animals remain hunkered down in hibernation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/3007px-Winter_Landscape_by_Caspar_David_Friedrich-1024x736.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Winter Landscape&quot; title=&quot;Winter Landscape by Caspar David Fredrich (1811)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Winter Landscape&lt;/i&gt; by Caspar David Fredrich (1811)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, despite this bleak scenery, we can still appreciate the significance of January if we look through the lens of ancient Roman mythology. January is named after the Roman god Janus, whom was the god of beginnings and endings, i.e. transitions. January itself is a time of transition from the old year to the new one, and times will always get tough during transitions, but the most important thing is to learn from the past and look forward to the future, no matter how dismal it may seem. In fact, Janus is usually depicted as having two faces since he looks to the past and the future, which is why he is also responsible for change and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time (or more precisely, the race against it), was a key part of our journey in January, especially with the school term starting again. Despite an increased workload, we still kept to our schedules and made great progress. This is our lengthiest consolidation post yet, but oh well, here are some of our major accomplishments this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dribbler&quot;&gt;Dribbler&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous design faced a problem of the ball “repelling” from the dribbler when it entered the catchment area. This was due to the fact that when the ball was dribbled, it would move backwards with a lot of force (especially considering how our dribbler spins the ball at 2000 RPM). The ball would hit the back wall which produces an equal reaction force that pushes the ball directly out of the dribbler. We did not face this problem in previous years because we never made our dribbler spin the ball so quickly before… 🙃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nKezmaD2Zs4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;video-caption&quot;&gt;This dribbler has an auto-kick function 🤔&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix this, a ramp was created on the bottom part of the catchment area, thus redirecting most of the backwards force of the ball diagonally upwards. This not only stopped the ball from bouncing out of the dribbler, but it also improved the dribbler’s performance since most of the backwards force of the ball was used to push itself up into the dribbler, which increased the rollers’ grip on the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/At1M0b0S7Zg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;video-caption&quot;&gt;Oddly satisfying...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mirror-lightweight&quot;&gt;Mirror (Lightweight)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very little has been revealed of our Soccer Lightweight robot’s actual design so far because we are experimenting with many new mechanics right now. We will definitely go into more detail when it gets closer to the competition after everything is finalised. However, all that needs to be known for now is that there will be a dribbler, a kicker, 4 motors and a 360 degree camera all somehow within that pesky 1.1kg limit 😉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the mirror, we cannot simply use the metal mirror of our Open robot due to weight constraints. Hence, we will be using the old method of molding mirror sheets instead, using the metal mirror as a mold. However, a big problem we faced with this method in the past was the mirror not being centralised since there was much room for error, be it during molding, cutting or gluing of the mirror sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix this, an enclosure was made using scrap Vex channels to keep the mirror sheet aligned with the mirror mold. An M3 hole is drilled into the centre of the mirror sheet using a Vex channel for alignment before being heated and molded. This 3mm hole is used to screw the molded mirror in to our 3D printed mirror stand, which connects directly to the mirror plate. By screwing the mirror in place, instead of gluing it like we did in the past, the mirror is guaranteed to be in the centre of the robot, plus the screw head acts as a “crosshair” for the mirror’s centre when calibrating the image’s centre point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8BhnuYHzYD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8BhnuYHzYD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8BhnuYHzYD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mirror making process!! Today we tried molding a mirror sheet with our new method for the first time and while there were many problems with the final product, at least the surface itself looked better than last time... 🙃 ⠀ 1: Random timelapse of cutting and screwing in the mirror sheet 2: Drilling a hole through the centre of the mirror sheet 3: Molding the mirror! 4: Molded mirror; hole at the tip warped slightly, mirror foil torn 😨 5, 6: Mirror attached to our mirror mount 7: Short clip from an OpenMV colour tracking program ⠀ More details about this mirror and many many other stuff coming up in our monthly consolidation blog post tommorow!! 😜 ~kfc [Soccer Lightweight] ⠀ #robocup #robocupjunior #robot #mirror #bozotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bozotics/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; ¡ßöZø 🗽 SqûãD!&lt;/a&gt; (@bozotics) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-02-01T12:12:55+00:00&quot;&gt;Feb 1, 2020 at 4:12am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, during our first try, the M3 hole was enlarged and warped slightly after molding. To fix this, we will try drilling the hole after making the mirror by using a 3D printed mold of the mirror as an alignment tool. The mirror sheet also tore, likely due to too much stretching during molding. Hence, we will try giving the sheet a little slack when screwing it on next time. We will also try using an actual heat gun, which heats up a larger area, so that the heating will be more even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these problems, the mirror surface itself produced a higher quality image as compared to our past molded mirrors since now the mirror mold is metal instead of 3D printed plastic, which meant the mirror sheet could be heated to a much higher temperature before molding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pcbs-lightweight&quot;&gt;PCBs (Lightweight)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 4 main layers in our Soccer Lightweight robot. The first layer is at the base and is the most complex plate since it has to hold many large components while having very limited space. Hence, all the components are placed in an extremely compact layout, even the battery slots in perfectly from the back to connect directly to the first layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pcb-1-1024x962.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EAGLE 1st layer top&quot; title=&quot;EAGLE 1st layer top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Top view of 1st layer as seen from EAGLE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the underside of this plate, we have our 48 light sensors, 36 of which are arranged in a ring of a 64mm radius (a huge improvement compared to our ring’s radius last year of only 40+mm), while the remaining 12 are placed in a 2x3 grid on the left and right. No other components are placed on the underside to prevent cases of accidental damage when the robot is moved around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/layer1-v2-1024x955.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fusion 1st layer bottom&quot; title=&quot;Fusion 1st layer bottom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Bottom view of 1st layer as seen from Fusion 360&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second layer is much emptier since its main job is just to support the dribbler and kicker, and hence large holes are also cut where possible in order to save weight. The main component it holds is the 5V buck converter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pcb1-1-1024x897.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EAGLE 2nd layer top&quot; title=&quot;EAGLE 2nd layer top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Does this 2nd layer even exist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the third layer (which is still a work in progress), will contain sensors such as the IR ring, Bluetooth module, camera, as well as our micro-controllers like the Teensy and STM32. The final layer is placed very high, above the mirror, and it holds the TOF sensors and compass. This allows the TOF sensors to sense over the goals, while keeping the compass as far away from the motors as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pcbs-open&quot;&gt;PCBs (Open)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Soccer Open robot has 4 main layers, of which 3 are PCBs. The first PCB is the base layer and will be slightly similar to our Lightweight robot’s first layer since they have similar outlines, motor driver placements and light sensor positions. However, there are additional components such as the boost converter for our solenoid and other all-round different arrangements of parts to fit our robot’s design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second PCB is actually on the third layer (the second layer is just a carbon fibre plate since all its space is occupied) and is the main PCB holding all the microcontrollers including the Raspberry Pi, Teensy, STM32s and also the remaining sensors like the compass and Bluetooth module. The battery (which lies on the second layer) is also plugged in to this layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Layer42-982x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EAGLE 3rd layer top&quot; title=&quot;EAGLE 3rd layer top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;3rd layer; a work in progress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final PCB is just above the third layer and it holds the Pi camera as well as the TOF sensors. It has an STM32 to process the TOF sensor readings as well as to control the 16 Neopixel LEDs on it that are used for debugging purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Layer4-1024x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EAGLE 4th layer top&quot; title=&quot;EAGLE 4th layer top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Top view of 4th layer as seen from EAGLE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, we should be able to finish designing our Open and Lightweight PCBs and sending them to be fabricated by the first week of February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gui&quot;&gt;GUI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made the &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; discovery that, for the whole of December working on the GUI for our Pi camera, when we were connecting to the Raspberry Pi from the laptop via SSH, it was connecting over WiFi instead of through a direct Ethernet connection 😂😂😂, which explained why the GUI’s video feed had such a low FPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the Raspberry Pi needed to act as a server and assign an IP address to the laptop in order for the laptop to connect through Ethernet, which we faced problems doing. Luckily, with help from the Arch Linux ARM forum, we were able to figure that out and can now connect to the Raspberry Pi directly over Ethernet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/test1-1024x512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Forum Screenshot&quot; title=&quot;Forum screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;camera&quot;&gt;Camera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous years, we have been using Python OpenCV to program our Pi camera, which came at the cost of speed. Due to Python’s Global Interpreter Lock (GIL), multi threading was not possible, and all the Python threading library was doing was simply switching between different threads rapidly instead of actually running tasks in parallel. Moreover, many basic functions like loops are significantly slower in Python than C++. Hence, we have decided to switch to programming both our camera and GUI on C++.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We initially created a program to simply capture frames from the camera to push it to its limits and we realised it was able to capture 640 by 480 images at 120 FPS! However, after adding a few basic OpenCV functions such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cvtColor&lt;/code&gt; (converting the image’s colour space), &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;inRange&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;clone&lt;/code&gt;, we were surprised at how slow they were running. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cvtColor&lt;/code&gt; itself took around 10ms, so one can just imagine how much longer more complicated functions like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;findContours&lt;/code&gt; would take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was when we realised our installation of OpenCV was not optimised. We enabled NEON (optimisation for ARM devices) and VFPV3 (floating point optimisation) in our CMake config before rebuilding and reinstalling OpenCV on our Raspberry Pi. With our new, optimised OpenCV library, the speed of the functions improved by a large margin; the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cvtColor&lt;/code&gt; function can now run below 2.5ms. Our target will be to process the frames at 50 FPS, which gives us about 20ms to process each frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, to finally stop our rampant spaghetti coding practices and start going “professional”, we will use classes to make our code more readable… 🙃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, January was a solid “meh”; we have definitely made progress but things seem like they can go much faster than this. Maybe its just the low after the New Year’s high I’m feeling here, or maybe our gears need time to be oiled up before going into overdrive… who knows? Personally, I would say I am entering February with a feeling of optimistic apprehension; optimism stemming from the hope that these robots could very well be the best robots in the history of our team, but apprehension stemming from the cognizance of the multitude of ways we could all fail spectacularly, especially when considering past experiences. But then again, maybe I worry too much… 🤷&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do know for sure is that February is going to be our make-it-or-break-it month. As long as we finish construction of our robots by the end of February, all should be well… 🤞&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kai Cong</name><email>161815w@student.hci.edu.sg</email></author><category term="Soccer Lightweight" /><category term="Soccer Open" /><category term="Electronics" /><category term="Mechanical" /><category term="Monthly" /><category term="Programming" /><summary type="html">January is here, with eyes that keenly glow, A frost-mailed warrior striding a shadowy steed of snow. Edgar Fawcett</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A December to Remember</title><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-december-to-remember/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A December to Remember" /><published>2020-01-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T12:40:00+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-december-to-remember</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-december-to-remember/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I heard a bird sing in the dark of December.
A magical thing and sweet to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oliver Herford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preliminary-thoughts&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preliminary thoughts…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;December 26 2019, 1:22 PM SGT. Thousands of people across Singapore had their heads tilted towards the sky, mouths agape, standing eerily still; the air was tense with conflicting feelings of awe, surprise, joy, uneasiness and even a tinge of fear. Without any context, one cannot fault a person for thinking that the Second Coming of Jesus Christ was happening at that very instant. Of course, people were watching in amazement not at the descent of some divinely being from the heavens, but the devouring of the Sun by the Moon in a rare annular solar eclipse, darkening the skies to an evening shade in the middle of the afternoon, while leaving a fiery ring of passion around the black, almost soulless circle of the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/eclipse-1190239_1920-1024x680.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Annular Solar Eclipse&quot; title=&quot;Annular solar eclipse&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Put a ring on it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eclipses have traditionally held a lot of symbolic meaning, but to have such a rare annular eclipse occurring just one day after Christmas, near the end of the decade; now that is a truly evocative way to end the year. In astrology, the Sun is typically associated with life and ambition, while the Moon is associated with our subconsciousness and emotions. Hence, a solar eclipse signifies the coalescence of one’s strongest desires with their internal self; the alignment of multiple identities into a new being of incomparable beauty in its own right. In other words, eclipses foretell of major changes beyond our control, but also remind us on the importance of honest self-reflection in the path of personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, much has changed in the month of December, albeit not as much progress as we would have wanted due to long periods of absence of multiple members and having other commitments. Nonetheless, here is a list of our main accomplishments this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mirror&quot;&gt;Mirror&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had sent our mirror design to be CNC lathed from aluminium in China last month and it arrived in early December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20191231_205320-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unpolished Mirror&quot; title=&quot;Unpolished mirror&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Unpolished mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mirror was mounted on a drill press and sanded with sandpaper of progressively higher grits, starting from 120 and ending with 2000. This was followed by 2 rounds of polishing, first with the more abrasive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.autosol.com/product_p/1000.htm&quot;&gt;Autosol&lt;/a&gt; metal polish and second with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.autobacs.com.sg/shop/car-care/nxt-generation-metal-polysh/&quot;&gt;Meguair’s Nxt Generation All Metal Polysh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20191226_182431-e1577863637569-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sanded Mirror&quot; title=&quot;Sanded mirror&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;After 2000 grit sanding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20191226_192236-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Polished Mirror&quot; title=&quot;Polished mirror&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;After polishing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results were acceptable, but scratches were still somewhat visible. Hence, we decided to redo the sanding process with wet sanding, and in true blue Hwa Chong Robotics style. The final image was slightly improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B6nazmanU2y/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B6nazmanU2y/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B6nazmanU2y/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MIRROR MEGA UPDATE: Turn on sound for maximum viewing pleasure!! 😌 ⠀ 1: Wet sanding on rooftop with human lathe 2: #rooftopgang 3: Post-sanding, pre-polished mirror; the trophies of our past silently judge our actions in the background 4: Simple ball and goal detection program + behind the scenes ball sweeping 5: What is the robot doing?? 🤔 6: New mirror plate + handle makes the robot look like it has six layers 7: The mirror plate has a maze on top. Don&amp;#39;t ask why. ⠀ Progress progress progress ~kfc [Soccer Open] #robocup #robocupjunior #bozotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bozotics/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; ¡ßöZø 🗽 SqûãD!&lt;/a&gt; (@bozotics) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-12-28T12:21:43+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 28, 2019 at 4:21am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Irresponsible acts were done responsibly...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, since the weight of the mirror is over 100 grams, the existing thin mirror stands were not strong enough to hold it steadily, causing the image to shift and vibrate when the robot is moving. Hence, a new mirror plate was designed, which connects directly to the four copper stands from the third layer. In addition, four thin stands were extended out from the trapezium mounts on the third layer, which prevents the plate from bending under the mirror’s weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/TEMP1-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mirror Plate Render&quot; title=&quot;Mirror plate render&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;8 stands for 1 mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, there is a maze on top of the mirror plate which fits a 2mm ball. Because, y’know, why not? 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dribbler&quot;&gt;Dribbler&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, the dribbler’s spring was quite strong, causing the dribbled ball to not have enough backwards force to fully enter the catchment area sometimes. We tried experimenting with an oil damper, but it was even stiffer than the existing spring and many models were too long to be implemented into our dribbler design easily.  Hence, we ended up simply using a weaker spring and made new rollers (as the old ones were rather worn out), and performance now is quite acceptable. This should be the final, completed version of the dribbler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20200102_140022-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dribbler Front View&quot; title=&quot;Dribbler front view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;New year, new &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;spring&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (ha, geddit?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pcb-for-testing&quot;&gt;PCB for testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a PCB which tests out some of the electrical components we will be using in our robot’s actual PCB. This PCB will arrive in early January 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pcb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Test PCB&quot; title=&quot;Test PCB&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Board layout for our test PCB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be testing a 12V to 5V/3.3V buck converter that uses a new IC from the one we used last year, as well as a 12V to 80V boost converter with a digital potentiometer to change the output voltage (for controlling the strength of our solenoid). We also have an STM32 breakout board. This year we used the Maple Mini (which uses the STM32 chip) as our secondary IC and we want to shrink it down to a very small footprint so that we could put more and further parallelize our robot’s processing power. We will also be experimenting with the CAN bus protocol for communication between the STM32 and Teensy. Other components we will be testing are the DRV8833 motor driver and light sensors (LED and phototransistors).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gui-for-camera&quot;&gt;GUI for Camera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A GUI was created to facilitate the calibration of the camera. It streams and processes the video feed of the Pi camera in real time. Experimentation with different parameters required to optimise our colour detection program, such as colour ranges, white balance and exposure, was conducted and we created programs to automate the process of identifying these parameters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/WhatsApp-Image-2020-01-01-at-12.22.40.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;GUI Screenshot&quot; title=&quot;GUI controls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;GUI Controls (top to bottom): Colour space, Zoom function, Region growing function, Exposure parameter, Save calibration data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/WhatsApp-Image-2020-01-01-at-12.22.54.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Region Growing Algorithm&quot; title=&quot;Region growing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Region growing algorithm on an object of interest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress overall is still on track and we are slated to finish construction by February, leaving a full month for programming before the Singapore Open. This month of December has been slower than desired, but just like how the tide recedes before a tsunami strikes, we are now more prepared than ever to forge new frontiers in the new year. 2020, here we go!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kai Cong</name><email>161815w@student.hci.edu.sg</email></author><category term="Soccer Open" /><category term="Electronics" /><category term="Mechanical" /><category term="Monthly" /><category term="Programming" /><summary type="html">I heard a bird sing in the dark of December. A magical thing and sweet to remember. Oliver Herford</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">December - Week 2</title><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/december-week-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="December - Week 2" /><published>2019-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T12:40:00+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/december-week-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/december-week-2/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-from-the-rainforest&quot;&gt;Working from the rainforest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A thousand apologies… our week 2 post came in a little late, but better than late than never! Doing productive work in Malaysia is really hard. There are tons of distractions around me – from endless errands to chatty relatives. Despite everything I managed to carve out small pockets of time in the middle of the night to get a little work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arch-linux&quot;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Raspi is running on Arch Linux so that there are minimal processes running in the background. This is our first step taken in optimising the camera module – to have a simple system to work with. I have also installed Arch Linux on my laptop which is currently dual booting. As installing C++ libraries on a Windows laptop is a troublesome process, and it seemed impossible after numerous tries, we thought that a Linux system would streamline this process. However, due to my lack of experience with Linux, I cannot boot Arch Linux on my laptop anymore. What happen was that i updated Arch Linux which caused the boot manager to lose the ability to boot it. From this, it is clear that I should have chosen a simpler distro like Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gui&quot;&gt;GUI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, in order to identify the different colour values or to change the program, we had to enter the Raspi using VNC. Now that our Raspi do not have a graphical user interface, we have to create a GUI to view the feed from the Picam. With this GUI we could add the functions we want accordingly. Some functions are to toggle between different colour modes instantly, select a region to identify its colour range, and to display such data in charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B6FE2_3nXJ0/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B6FE2_3nXJ0/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B6FE2_3nXJ0/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Day-bew - Step 1 of making GUI to debug Raspi done! I can now access the Raspi camera feed from my laptop with just one ethernet cable and one click. The configurable colour mode is just a start, more to come! -JT [Soccer Open] #bozotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bozotics/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; ¡ßöZø 🗽 SqûãD!&lt;/a&gt; (@bozotics) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-12-15T04:15:46+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 14, 2019 at 8:15pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using the sockets library I could send the frames captured on the Picam to my laptop which is then further processed based on the different settings selected on the GUI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, more functions would be added to the GUI. One of those functions would be a text editor where I can edit the program inside of the Raspi. Also, after confirming the different calibrations values i.e. colour values and exposure it will be saved in a text file in the Raspi which will be accessed by the main program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pi-camera&quot;&gt;Pi Camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were calibrating the camera this year, we realised that the shade of orange varied when the robot is placed at different parts of the field. This made our colour values unreliable. Therefore, we have looked into white balance calibration as we plan to disable the auto w/b function in the Pi camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the shade of orange might be constantly changing we could predict the next colour range using the current and past few colour ranges, this allows our program to be more dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juggling between work and life in Malaysia is tough. Avoid using Arch Linux as a start, opt for Ubuntu or something simpler. Right now, we are optimising the camera and its calibration process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Justin Tan</name><email>151548b@student.hci.edu.sg</email></author><category term="Soccer Open" /><category term="Programming" /><category term="Weekly" /><summary type="html">Working from the rainforest A thousand apologies… our week 2 post came in a little late, but better than late than never! Doing productive work in Malaysia is really hard. There are tons of distractions around me – from endless errands to chatty relatives. Despite everything I managed to carve out small pockets of time in the middle of the night to get a little work done.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">December - Week 1</title><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/electronics-and-rescue-updates-december-week-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="December - Week 1" /><published>2019-12-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T12:40:00+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/electronics-and-rescue-updates-december-week-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/electronics-and-rescue-updates-december-week-1/">&lt;p&gt;Can’t really think of a good intro like the previous post, and can’t find that many photos as well, so here is a very wordy introduction / progress update for our Rescue Line and Soccer Open robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;electronic-components&quot;&gt;Electronic Components&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our previous robot, we have designed custom PCBs for our use, utilising different SMD ICs. However, not all of the different circuits worked as expected, and we ended up reverting to some through hole pre-made modules such as for our step-down and boost circuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_20190401_223008-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dismantled Old Robot&quot; title=&quot;Dismantled old robot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Look at the step down module on the top layer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, in a bid to make our design smaller and fit within the future 20cm diameter size limit, we needed to decrease the amount of these modules used and try to integrate everything into our PCB. These component selections were a result of our previous year’s experience and extensive research into potential alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;microcontrollers&quot;&gt;Microcontrollers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue to use a Teensy 3.5/3.6 as our main processor as well as a Raspberry Pi + Raspi Camera combo for ball detection. However, for a secondary processor doing tasks such as pinging our distance sensors, we have changed from an Arduino Nano to a Maple Mini in our previous robots.
This year, we are trying to embed a STM32F103 IC directly into our PCB, thus saving a lot of space previously used for pins. Once we have tested and programmed our STM32 circuit, we are planning on using many of these throughout our robot, one on each layer in order to decrease the amount of wires running up and down our robot. This also frees up valuable processing power on our main processor for potentially more complex strategies and localisation algorithms.
We are testing SWD for use with our STM32 rather than programming through USB like we used to. We are also testing SPI for communication with our main controller, however it has been problematic so far and we are probably reverting to UART (since there are 6 UART on the Teensy anyways). I2C proved to be too unreliable and affected by noise for us to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;motor-drivers&quot;&gt;Motor Drivers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our robot would be powered by ST VNH5019 motor drivers, these were cheap and reliable as we have used them for our previous robot.
We had considered using the smaller VNH5050 motor drivers, also made by ST, however we could not get the voltage output to scale with our PWM input and thus decided to go with the slightly bigger VNH5019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;light-sensors&quot;&gt;Light Sensors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For out detection, we went with SMD LEDs and the TEMT6000 SMD Phototransistors. We would be using 48 of these together with 3 CD74HC4067 multiplexer ICs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mouse-sensor&quot;&gt;Mouse Sensor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We briefly experimented with a PMW3360 Mouse Sensor for localisation in our robot, however that was short-lived as we blew both the sensors we bought due to the low operating voltages.
We did think about other mouse sensors such as those from Avago however online reviews showed that the PMW3360 was more accurate. We also considered a PMW3901 optical flow sensor, but it needed to be positioned at least 8cm from the ground and we did not have the space to create a 8cm high hole in our robot.
This year, hopefully we can get the PMW3360 to work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;distance-sensors&quot;&gt;Distance Sensors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went from using SR04 ultrasonic sensors to a VL53L0X last year. However, we faced problems getting the VL53L0X sensors we had to change I2C addresses so that we could access more than 1, thus this year we are changing to the upgraded VL53L1X TOF sensor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;imu&quot;&gt;IMU&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have had very bad experiences with various IMUs before, starting out with a Robot Electronics CMPS11 which couldn’t calibrate properly and randomly stopped working, then moving on to the MPU9250, Pololu MinIMU-9 and AltIMU-10, and finally the BNO055. However, while the BNO055 worked perfectly while testing, in 2 separate competitions (2018 Robocup Canada and 2019 Robocup Singapore) it failed to work well, going from bad readings to hanging the whole robot and not responding. We have also tried the Adafruit Precision NXP IMU, and while it worked really well in the example code, running the filter code together with our main code did not work very well.
This year, we are experimenting with putting the BNO055 on its own I2C line and attached to its own separate microcontroller, as well as Adafruit’s IMU with its own separate microcontroller to process and filter the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;power&quot;&gt;Power&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our previous robot, we used a TPS5450 for our 3.3v output, a LM2596 (on a module) for our 5v output and a LM2587 (on a module) for our 60v solenoid output. However, the TPS5450 ran pretty hot last year, and the LM2596 module was quite huge. We would be conducting some load and efficiency tests to determine whether we should change the TPS5450 to a more efficient IC, and we would also be integrating our 5v and 60v supply into our PCB with a TPS5430 and LM2587.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;others&quot;&gt;Others&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are using a HC05 Bluetooth module for communication between robots and debug purposes and a Neopixel ring which lights up which direction the ball / goal is in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rescue-line-components&quot;&gt;Rescue Line components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are experimenting with TCS3200 and TCS34725 color sensors to detect the green square. On one hand, the TCS3200 requires a lot of digital ports and computationally expensive pulseIn() commands to get the readings, however the TCS34725 requires an I2C multiplexer since its I2C addressed cannot be changed (to my knowledge).
We are also using a DRV8833 Dual Motor Driver IC to power our 2 (old) Faulhaber 2224 motors. We chose this over the popular TB6612 since it has over-current protection, and we don’t need the higher input voltage since we are running on a 2S 7.2V battery for rescue line.
Lastly, for our light sensors we would be using the same TEMT6000 in our Soccer robots. However, to interface our light sensors with our main processor, we would have a STM32 on each light sensor board and use SPI between them since there are limited UART interfaces in the STM32F103.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oops, that was a little too wordy…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rescue-line-robot-base&quot;&gt;Rescue Line Robot Base&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is not obvious from the above, my main expertise is in electronics and I have not dabbled too much with 3D CAD designing in the past. However, now I need to design an entire robot on my own (with DY but he also doesn’t really know 3D CAD yay!). In order to design this I have went from Fusion 360 to Autocad and back to Fusion 360 again, and realised that my workflow was completely wrong and messy, and now I am redoing the whole design. Great times! 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I have managed to kind-of come up with a base design with my ghetto designing skills:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B5m7bQgHkDa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B5m7bQgHkDa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B5m7bQgHkDa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Day 2+??: Finished the base of the robot for now, 9 hr print ahead, hopefully the gears don&amp;#39;t end up grinding too much. Also finished some slave work and claims!! 🎉 ~pajiao [rescue]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bozotics/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; ¡ßöZø 🗽 SqûãD!&lt;/a&gt; (@bozotics) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-12-03T11:16:07+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 3, 2019 at 3:16am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But unexperienced me decided to make the entire base one solid 3d printed chunk rather than split it up, and thus used up 100g of filament in one shot!!! Nevermind, at least it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B55U4tcnVaR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B55U4tcnVaR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B55U4tcnVaR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Day ??????????: vroom vroom this is with an undersized gear which is barely contacting the other one so I think this is a win! ~pajiao [rescue]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bozotics/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; ¡ßöZø 🗽 SqûãD!&lt;/a&gt; (@bozotics) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-12-10T14:45:14+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 10, 2019 at 6:45am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redesign coming right up but not before my test PCB is complete…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my time last year was spent on FLL so the PCB was completed only like 2 weeks before the competition… Lets just hope that with no FLL this year it can be completed a little earlier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hcbozo&quot;&gt;github.com/hcbozo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jing Heng</name><email>151436j@student.hci.edu.sg</email></author><category term="Rescue Line" /><category term="Soccer Open" /><category term="Electronics" /><category term="Weekly" /><summary type="html">Can’t really think of a good intro like the previous post, and can’t find that many photos as well, so here is a very wordy introduction / progress update for our Rescue Line and Soccer Open robots.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A November Consolidation</title><link href="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-november-consolidation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A November Consolidation" /><published>2019-12-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-24T13:37:11+08:00</updated><id>https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-november-consolidation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bozo.infocommsociety.com/blog/a-november-consolidation/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;November at its best – with a sort of delightful menace in the air.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anne Bosworth Greene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-few-thoughts&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A few thoughts…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November is a month of transition from the autumn to winter season. The beautiful spectrum of striking red, flashy orange, and glowing yellow autumn leaves wither and fall, littering the ground with their dry, brown, shriveled bodies, showing no signs of life other than a short flutter from the occasional gust of wind. Days grow shorter and nights grow longer. The cool, crisp air of autumn becomes the bitter, frigid weather of winter. It is no wonder why to some, the month of November symbolizes the approach of death; the nearing of an end of some metaphorical era of one’s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Bricher-Autumn_Landscape-1024x524.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Autumn Landscape&quot; title=&quot;Autumn Landscape by Alfred Thomson Bricher(1870)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Autumn Landscape&lt;/i&gt; by Alfred Thomson Bricher(1870)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I prefer to take a more optimistic outlook. Under the guise of grimness lies a sea of wisdom. Rather than death, November for me represents a rebirth or a reinvention, a chance to impart revolutionary changes to oneself. As a month near the end of the year but just before the holiday month of December, November creates the perfect setting to do some serious self-reflection; to take stock of one’s successes and failures and learn from the year’s worth of experiences. Our RoboCup experience this year was a failure due to a multitude of inexcusable mistakes such as overextending our workloads and poor time management. We have definitely learnt from our mistakes and have sworn to never repeat them again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, since mid-October, we have made progress in our Soccer Open robots by leaps and bounds and here is a consolidation of some key moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dribbler&quot;&gt;Dribbler&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first draft of the dribbler’s 3D design was actually completed way back in August, but due to pesky exams and waiting of Taobao shipments, it was only fully assembled in mid-November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/exploded-dribbler-2-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Exploded Dribbler&quot; title=&quot;Exploded view of dribbler&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Exploded view of dribbler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dribbler is powered by an 820kV brushless motor through a 2:5 ratio gear train, giving the bar an estimated 3900 RPM when running on our 12V batteries. This means that the ball will be spinning at over 2000 RPM!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dribbler’s rollers are coated with a layer of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zener.com.sg/product/araldite-kitchen-and-bathroom-silicone/&quot;&gt;silicone&lt;/a&gt; to have high grip on the ball. The whole dribbler module has a pivot point at its back with a spring suspension to allow for the bar to move up and down slightly, thus absorbing impact and giving better control over the dynamic movements of the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20191113-2_3-0-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dribbler Gearbox&quot; title=&quot;Dribbler's gearbox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Dribbler's gearbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20191113-2_3-3-1024x498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assembled Dribbler&quot; title=&quot;Assembled dribbler&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Assembled dribbler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slight adjustments of the dribbler’s position were done through trial and error to adjust the angle the dribbler pivots to. While results were satisfactory, the ball still does move in and out when dribbled, and thus we will be experimenting with different spring strengths and even an oil damper for our suspension system soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B4y3GI-HftJ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B4y3GI-HftJ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B4y3GI-HftJ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Day 3: Man took a well deserved 4 day break and came back to assemble a surprisingly good DRIBBLER 💪😙 #flex #nokick ~kfc [Soccer Open] #robocup #robocupjunior #bozotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bozotics/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; ¡ßöZø 🗽 SqûãD!&lt;/a&gt; (@bozotics) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-11-13T05:57:47+00:00&quot;&gt;Nov 12, 2019 at 9:57pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mirror&quot;&gt;Mirror&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following a few rounds of experimentation, we finalised on a mirror shape that is a combination of a cone and a hyperbola. The hyperbolic base of the mirror enlarges objects near the robot with minimal deformation, while the conic part of the mirror enlarges the goals and maintains the roughly rectangular shape of the field lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/5-48deg-centre-res-1024x787.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mirror Render&quot; title=&quot;Robot's POV&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Robot's POV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having faced many problems with the molding method for making our mirror in previous years, we have decided to try manufacturing our mirror this time by sending our design to China for aluminium CNC lathing, followed by polishing it up ourselves. Fingers crossed! 🤞&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2d-simulation&quot;&gt;2D Simulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our revamp of robot strategy, we are planning to create smarter, more human-like play by introducing decision trees as well as special offensive/defensive manoeuvres (top secret for now!). Hence, we created a semi-realistic 2D simulator using Python with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arcade.academy/&quot;&gt;Arcade&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pymunk.org/&quot;&gt;Pymunk&lt;/a&gt; libraries. As of now, we have a robot running a simple ball chasing with goal aiming/shooting program, but this simulator will surely come into great use in the future as we further develop our robot strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/t_YrVmQF8q4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November has been eventful and rewarding, with everything having come together rather smoothly (quite literally). With the robot design basically completed, the other half of the robot’s hardware, Electronics, will be the focus for the month of December. With our fully custom made PCBs and plans for embedded micro-controllers, this December journey will surely be an interesting one.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kai Cong</name><email>161815w@student.hci.edu.sg</email></author><category term="Soccer Open" /><category term="Mechanical" /><category term="Monthly" /><category term="Simulation" /><summary type="html">November at its best – with a sort of delightful menace in the air. Anne Bosworth Greene</summary></entry></feed>